SIRVAN DOUKCHI

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT



0406 471 171



Sirvansh@gmail.com



www.Sirvan.Dev



https://github.com/SirvanD



Sydney, NSW

SKILLS

Language/Framework

- JavaScript/TypeScript
- React
- Next.JS
- Node.JS

- Ruby
- Redux/Context API
- Github CI/CD
- Unit Testing
- Jenkins
- Jira Workflow
- Jest/React Testing
- Library

Cloud/Database/Tech

- Architect
- MongoDB PostgreSQL
- Google Firebase
- Tailwind CSS
- Boostrap
- MaterialUI
- Adobe Experiences Manager

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Bootcamp General Assembly

Oct 2021 - March 2022

Immersive 3 months full-time bootcamp learning foundations and implementing multiple full-stack applications of JS, Ruby, React, NodeJS and CRUD.

Master of Information Technology University of Wollongong

July 2016 - July 2018

Graduated with a Distinction average followed by a 3 months internship placement.

Key subjects:

- · Project and Change Management,
- · Systems Integration,
- · IT security and Risk Management.

PROFILE

Full-stack developer, with hands-on experience, passionate and selfmotivated to actualise ideas all the way to implementing in browsers in a user-friendly and modern interface. I am committed to continually advancing my knowledge of relevant technologies including JavaScript, React JS/Native, TypeScript, Redux, Node.JS, and more.

I am also a footballer and very fond of my meticulously picked podcast shows!

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Vodafone Australia (TPG Telecom)

July 2022 - Present

- Develop customer-facing solutions in a modern stack using React TS, Customized Styled Component configurable through own CMS.
- Develop APIs to be consumed by frontend apps in NextJS stack with functional components, and React Hooks to handle application life-cycle processes
- Participate in daily standups, sprint updates, and shoulder checks with UX and QA teams discussing updates, change requests, and demonstrations.
- Participate in support roster, with duties: deploy weekly releases, on call for arising issues including productions and escalation, AWS Cloudwatch logs troubleshooting, participate in bridge calls with 3rd party support teams.
- Built unit tests using Jest and react-testing-library to pass a strict coverage threshold forced by pre-commit hooks.
- Worked closely with clients to establish specifications and system designs. Used Zeplin and Figma to collaborate with UX
- Maintain full responsiveness while using Flexbox, grid in different scenarios, and while building custom component for UX library.
- Utilising Storybook for showcasing UI components and test different viewports and scenarios.
- Utilise CI/CD pipeline to deploy both frontend and backend solutions with distinct phases of dev, sit, and prod in GIT and use Jenkins to deploy middleware.
- Experienced working with Adobe Launch and Experience Manager for content management.
- Using Braintree payment SDK to develop a payment gateway for production website with customised hosted fields with validation and alert boxes for different errors
- Revamping a significant component on the main page for a responsive and adjustable mobile-view layout.

IT Analyst

Clayton UTZ

Dec 2020 - Sep 2021

· Active directory administration, Microsoft Azure user groups, forest and domain management, shared drives, and application of SCCM, RDP, Logmein, and Skype remote consoles for assisting remote clients.

SIRVAN DOUKCHI

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT



0406 471 171



Sirvansh@gmail.com



www.Sirvan.Dev



https://github.com/SirvanD



Sydney, NSW

SKILLS

Language/Framework

- JavaScript/TypeScript Github Cl/CD
- React
- Next.JS
- Node.JS
- Ruby
- Redux/Context API
- Unit Testing
- Jenkins
- Jira Workflow
- Jest/React Testing Library

Cloud/Database/Tech

- Architect
- MongoDB PostgreSQL
- Google Firebase
- Tailwind CSS
- Boostrap
- MaterialUI
- Adobe Experiences Manager

IT Support Officer

Melbourne Institue of Technology

Oct 2019 - Dec 2020

- · Liaise with internal staff and students over the phone and on-site
- utilising HEAT ticket management for level 1 and 2 services and
- escalation of level 3 and security concerns to infrastructure teams.

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING PROJECTS

My Taxi www

Tech Stack: React Native - Redux - Tailwind CSS

Uber-inspired mobile application, where based on origin and destination information provided by the user, will show markers and the path from origin to target

Princes Theatre www

Tech Stack: JavaScript - React - SASS - JEST (React Testing Library)

Front-End App where Star Wars fans can find an affordable option between two streaming providers. Using an inconsistent API to retrieve information and recall to receive a response. Components tested using Jest and API call mocked for integration test.

Portfolio www



Tech Stack: React - NextJS - SASS - CSS3

Professional portfolio designed with a mobile view first in mind and a minimalist look. UX and color contrast principles are followed.

BookShelf www



Tech Stack: React - NodeJS / Express - MongoDB for Database - Firebase Authentication - Material UI - Google Books API and REST API

A community library Full-Stack application where users can sign up/log in using own account or Gmail and donate/borrow books.

INTERNSHIP AND ACTIVITY

IT Support Officer - Part-Time

University of Wollongong

Jul 2019 - Oct 2019

Provide effective level one support to the UOW community for all service requests, including incident diagnosis

IT Technician Intern - Part-Time

CareSouth

Sep 2017 - Dec 2017

Observing and learning organizational skills, teamwork skills, and practicing academic knowledge at industry level within a friendly, encouraging, and professional team.